Abhinand NS

DevOps Engineer

An IT professional with over 2+ years of experience specializing in network and server management for various government and private companies. My greatest strength is business awareness, which enables me to permanently streamline infrastructure and applications.

Calicut, Kerala +91 8281878286 mails2abhinand@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/abhinandns/

www.abhinand.in

EXPERIENCE

Accubits Technologies Inc, Trivandrum — *DevOps Engineer*

July 2020 - PRESENT

Works on Software Development Lifecycle and has an outright understanding of various automation tools for developing digital pipelines (CI/CD pipelines). Tools Used: AWS, GCP, Azure, Alibaba Cloud, On-premises servers, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Git, Jenkins, Firewalls, Grafana, Prometheus, Ansible.

KLA Live Webcasting Project, Trivandrum — *Back End Developer*

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

Working with live video telecasting servers of Kerala legislative assembly. Maintenance, Monitoring, and data backup of several redundant servers containing terabytes of video files with the associated database. The job demands a lot of responsibility, as the slightest mistakes could make up news headlines for the next day.

EDUCATION

College of Engineering Attingal, Trivandrum — B.Tech

2015-2019

Computer Science Engineering in APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University with CGPA

Certifications

Advanced Diploma System Security Analyst — Nov 2019

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ELECTRONICS & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (NIELIT)

SKILLS

Communicative Skills

Strategic Planning

Team Building

My Confidence

Linux/Shell Scripting ★★★★

Networking ★★★★

DevOps ★★★★☆

Python ****

NoSql, MySql ★★★★☆

IoT Devices ★★★☆☆

LANGUAGES

Malayalam, English, Hindi, Sanskrit